<div class="wiki-content maincontent"><p><strong>Description</strong></p><p><span style="color: rgb(102,0,51);">Apache ActiveMQ is a popular and powerful open source message-oriented middleware. Apache ActiveMQ is fast, supports many cross language clients and protocols, comes with easy to use enterprise integration patterns and many advanced features while fully supporting JMS 2.0, AMQP 1.0, MQTT, Stomp and REST.</span></p><p><strong><span style="color: rgb(102,0,51);">Activity</span></strong></p><ul><li><span style="color: rgb(255,0,0);"><span style="color: rgb(0,51,102);"><span style="color: rgb(0,0,0);">ActiveMQ</span></span></span><ul><li><span style="color: rgb(0,0,0);">Work continues on bug fixes and hardening of the ActiveMQ 5.x broker.<br clear="none"></span></li><li><span style="color: rgb(0,0,0);">New 5.15.0 release is out which now requires Java 8 and includes the latest Camel 2.19.0 release</span></li></ul><span style="color: rgb(0,0,0);"><br clear="none"></span></li><li><span style="color: rgb(0,0,0);">ActiveMQ Artemis</span></li></ul><ul><li style="list-style-type: none;background-image: none;"><ul><li><span style="color: rgb(0,0,0);">Continued work on adding new features with several active discussions both on the mailing list and in JIRA and PR comments around the implementation of those features and their affect on existing usecases from members of the community. <br clear="none"></span></li><li><span style="color: rgb(0,0,0);">Improving AMQP support</span></li><li><span style="color: rgb(0,0,0);">Many fixes around compatibility with older clients.</span></li></ul></li></ul><ul><li><span style="color: rgb(0,0,0);">ActiveMQ Other</span><ul><li><span style="color: rgb(0,0,0);">The community has opened up a call for new Logo's for the project website, a vote to pick a winner is expected late July.<br clear="none"></span></li></ul></li></ul><p><strong>PMC changes</strong></p><ul><li>Last PMC addition:&#160;<span style="color: rgb(34,34,34);">Thu Oct 27 2016 (Clebert Suconic)</span></li><li>Currently 24 PMC members</li></ul><p><strong>Committer base changes</strong></p><ul><li>Currently 59 committers.&#160;</li><li>Francesco Nigro was added as a committer on Tue May 09 2017&#160;</li></ul><p><strong>Releases</strong></p><ul><li>5.14.5 was released on Sun Apr 16 2017</li><li>5.15.0 was released on Thu Jun 29 2017</li><li>ActiveMQ Artemis 1.5.5 was released on Sun May 14 2017</li><li>ActiveMQ Artemis 2.1.0 was released on Sun May 14 2017</li><li>ActiveMQ CLI Tools 0.1.0 was released on Sun May 07 2017</li></ul><p>Report submitted: 11 Jul 2017</p><p>(Most of this information is pulled from <a shape="rect" href="https://reporter.apache.org/">reporter.apache.org</a>)</p></div>

