<div class="wiki-content maincontent"><h2>Broker Properties URI</h2><p>From version 4.2 of ActiveMQ onwards the Broker Properties URI allows you to <link><page ri:content-title="Run Broker"></page><plain-text-link-body>run a configured broker</plain-text-link-body></link> by referencing a properties file which could be on the classpath, a local file or a remote URL.</p><h4>Syntax</h4><p><strong>properties:name</strong></p><p>Where name is some name which is resolved on the classpath, as a local file or a remote URL which points to the properties file used to configure the broker.</p><h5>Example URI</h5><p>The following examples show variations in using the URI</p><structured-macro ac:macro-id="632155fb-8fe5-43c9-bb92-058d3e71366f" ac:name="noformat" ac:schema-version="1"><plain-text-body>properties:/foo/bar.properties
properties:foo.properties
properties:http://foo.com/foo.properties
</plain-text-body></structured-macro><p>Here is <a shape="rect" href="http://svn.apache.org/repos/asf/activemq/trunk/activemq-unit-tests/src/test/resources/org/apache/activemq/config/broker.properties">an example properties file</a></p><structured-macro ac:macro-id="8e337744-7484-4c40-afec-e78bdd572746" ac:name="noformat" ac:schema-version="1"><plain-text-body>## ---------------------------------------------------------------------------
## Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one or more
## contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file distributed with
## this work for additional information regarding copyright ownership.
## The ASF licenses this file to You under the Apache License, Version 2.0
## (the "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance with
## the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at
## 
## http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
## 
## Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
## distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
## WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
## See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
## limitations under the License.
## ---------------------------------------------------------------------------
# START SNIPPET: example
useJmx = false
persistent = false
brokerName = Cheese
# END SNIPPET: example
</plain-text-body></structured-macro></div>

