<div class="wiki-content maincontent"><p>Inspired greatly by <a shape="rect" href="http://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/talks.html">Gregor and Erik's great talk at TSSJS 2006</a> we've started to add some visualisation plugins into Apache ActiveMQ.</p>

<h3>Connection visualisation</h3>

<p>There is a <strong>&lt;connectionDotFilePlugin/&gt;</strong> broker plugin which generates a <a shape="rect" href="http://www.graphviz.org/">DOT file</a> such as <a shape="rect" href="visualisation.data/ActiveMQConnections.dot">this example</a> representing the connections, sessions, producers, consumers and the destinations they are using.</p>

<p><image><attachment ri:filename="ActiveMQConnections.png"></attachment></image></p>

<h3>Destination visualisation</h3>

<p>There is a <strong>&lt;destinationDotFilePlugin/&gt;</strong> broker plugin which generates a <a shape="rect" href="http://www.graphviz.org/">DOT file</a> such as <a shape="rect" href="visualisation.data/ActiveMQDestinations.dot">this example</a> whenever a destination is created or destroyed in the broker. You can then turn this dot file into a nicely rendered image such as the one below.</p>

<p><image ac:thumbnail="true"><attachment ri:filename="ActiveMQDestinations.png"></attachment></image></p>

<h2>A note for OS X users</h2>

<p>If you are using OS X then you can open the DOT file using <a shape="rect" href="http://www.pixelglow.com/graphviz/">graphviz</a> which will then automatically re-render if it changes, so you end up with a real time graphical representation of the topic and queue hierarchies.</p>

<p>Also if you want to edit the layout a little before adding it to a wiki to distribute to your team, open the DOT file with <a shape="rect" href="http://www.omnigroup.com/applications/omnigraffle/">OmniGraffle</a> then just edit away <emoticon ac:name="smile"></emoticon></p>

<h2>Visualisation Wish List</h2>

<p>There are so many different things we could visualise; our only limitation is our imagination. So if you have any ideas for what we could visualise please add something to our <link><page ri:content-title="Visualisation Wish List"></page></link></p>

<h1>External Open Source Tools</h1>

<ul><li><a shape="rect" href="http://hawt.io/">hawtio</a> is an open source HTML5 web application for working with Apache ActiveMQ and Apache Camel. It lets you create topics/queues, browse queues or send messages to destinations as well as visualising Camel routes and working with Camel endpoints along with viewing logs and metric charting etc.</li><li><a shape="rect" href="https://github.com/fusesource/fuseide">Fuse IDE</a> is an open source set of eclipse plugins for working with Apache ActiveMQ and Apache Camel. Its got tooling for runtime browsing of queues, creating topics/queues. You can drag and drop messages to/from ActiveMQ destinations and Camel endpoints</li></ul>
</div>

